翻译校对       Mam
日  听      大海
日听校对       Syura
翻译        阿里斯
时间轴       糖果酱
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
Do you remember when we first
started playing this game?
最初にこのゲームを始めたときのこと
覚えてるか？
Let's go make a snowman together.
一緒に雪だるま作ろう
Which one are you talking to?
どっちに言ってるの？
Both of you, of course.
もちろん二人によ
There's nobody named "Both of you" here.
「ふたり」なんて名前の子はいないよ
I'm talking to you,
Hikaru-chan and Kaoru-chan.
光ちゃんと馨ちゃんに言ってるの
Okay then,
じゃあさ　どっちが光で　どっちが馨か　分かる
which one of us is Hikaru,
and which one is Kaoru? Can you tell?
Let's play the
"Which one is Hikaru- kun game"!
どっちが光君でしょうかゲーム
"Music Room #3"
"The Host Club is now open for business"
Now then,
さあて　どっちが光か分かるかな
can you tell which one of us is Hikaru?
Oh, this is hard.
え～難しい～
They look too much alike.
そっくりすぎ～
There's never been a girl
いままで　本当に見抜いた子は一人もいないからね
who could really tell us apart before.
What a ridiculous game.
なんてくだらないゲームだ
Huh? Something you don't like about it?
あれ　なんか気に入らない
It's not just that.
ていうか　二人の人気がいまいち理解できない
I can't quite figure out why
you two are so popular.
That's telling us.
言ってくれるね
Apparently, Haruhi doesn't...
どうもハルヒは
...understand the merits of
having twins in the Host Club.
ホスト部における双子のメリットを理解していないようだね
Listen here.
いいか
Just having a couple of
good-looking homosexuals
美形同士のホモと言うだけでも十分ポイントは高い
earns plenty of high points.
And making a show of teetering between
that and friendship is also desirable.
そして　友情との狭間で揺れる演出も好ましいが
But in our case, being twins,
僕らの場合
双子というこの上ないタブーを武器にしているわけ
we get to use this most
forbidden of taboos as a weapon.
On top of that, there's the scenario
of having two people,
その上
そんな絆の深い二人に同時に愛されてしまうという構図
who have such deep ties to each other,
loving you at the same time.
It's the ultimate young
woman's romance, right?
乙女の究極のロマンだろう
Er... I...
わたくし　もう駄目です
I can't bear any more!
Hikaru! Kaoru!
光　馨
部のホームページ管理は真面目にやるという条件で
I let you have control of the
club's homepage on the condition
that you would take it seriously!
任せたんだよな
だからやってますよ　真面目に
And we are taking it seriously.
We were up until dawn
last night working on it.
昨日だって明け方までかけて
作ったのが　この画面か
And this is the screen that you made!?
Haru-chan, you look great!
ハルちゃん　格好いい
セクシー
When!?
いつだ
When did you take
nude photos of Haruhi!?
いつハルヒのヌードなんて撮ったぁぁぁ
"Yes, that's the pose.
そう　そのポーズだ
That's a nice expression.
いい表情だよ
Once we're done here, we'll let you
have all the fancy tuna you want...
これが終わったら
大トロ好きなだけ食べさせてあげるからね
"Fancy tuna"
...that you want... that you want..."
あげるからね　あげるからね
とかやったのか　やったのか
Is that what you did!?
You're intensely delusional.
妄想激しすぎ
It's a composite photo, of course.
合成写真に決まってるでしょう
Composite?
合成？
"You mean, photoshopped?"
We did a good job, didn't we?
よく出来てるでしょう
Magnificent skill, if I do say so myself.
我ながら　すばらしい技術
You idiots! What a wasted use
of your skills! Have some shame!
馬鹿者　技術の無駄遣いだ　恥を知れ
But if you are going to do it,
どうせやるなら　このアイドル写真集と合成しなさい
composite her with
this idol photo collection.
That would be silly, sir.
It would be quicker...
馬鹿だな　殿　こんなの
...to ask her directly
to wear that stuff.
本人に直接着せたほうが早いよ
Y-yeah, I could ask her.
そ　そか　本人に
What do you think about this?
これなんか　どうかな
Why do you have that?
なんで持ってんの？
Haruhi- kun looks fantastic!
ハルヒ君　素敵
Still, like Tamaki-sama says,
でも　環様のおっしゃるように
I'd sure like to see Haruhi- kun
dressed in women's clothes.
ハルヒ君の女装姿も見てみたいわね
Haruhi- kun is so cute, I'm sure
they would look good on him.
ハルヒ君　可愛いから　きっと似合っちゃうわ
Would you stop compositing pictures
of me without my permission?
やめてよね　勝手に変な合成写真作るのを
Just what do you take
other people to be?
人を一体なんだと思ってるの
Isn't that obvious? Toys.
決まってんじゃん
オモチャ
"The Host Club continues
to be open for business"
So you see,
だからさ　退屈な人生を楽しく過ごすには
in order to enjoy
an otherwise boring life...
...you need to have some stimulating toys.
刺激的なおもちゃが必要なんだよ
I am not a toy!
自分はおもちゃじゃない
Toys...
おもちゃ
おもちゃ　おもちゃ
Toys... toys...
If you like toys, then by all means,
come to my club, the Black Magic Club.
おもちゃが好きなら　ぜひ我が部　黒魔術部へ
We've opened a marketplace
of the world's black magic curios.
世界の黒魔術道具市　開催中
We're also always holding mass.
ミサも常時やってまーす
If you come now, I'll make sure
you get this handsome curse doll,
今なら漏れなく　素敵な呪い人形
"Black Magic Club President,
Nekozawa Umehito"
Belzenef, as my present.
ベルゼネフをプレゼント
Why is he talking through
a crack in the door?
なんで　あんな隙間から
For that matter,
ていうか　ドアなんかあったっけ
has there always been a door there?
Nekozawa- senpai doesn't like
brightly-lit places.
猫沢先輩は明るいところがお嫌いだからな
You must not have anything
to do with that man.
あの人に関わってはいけない
If you do, you will
definitely become cursed.
関われば　必ず呪われる
Do you have any basis for that claim?
何か根拠でも
Yes. It was during the tests
at the end of last year...
そう　あれは昨年度末の試験の時のことだ
Ah, it's terrifying just talking about it.
あ　口にするのも恐ろしいが
Tamaki- kun, good morning.
環君　おはよう
Good morning.
おはよう
That was the day that I accidentally
stepped on that cursed doll, Belzenef...
俺が誤ってつい
あの呪い人形ベルゼネフを踏んでしまったあの日
The test I took immediately
afterward had been enumerated
直後受けた試験では
わけの分からぬ呪詛のごとき文字が羅列され
in incomprehensible letters,
as though it had been cursed!
Warily, I looked at those around me,
but I knew none of them!
不審に思い　辺りを見渡せば
見知らぬ人間ばかりの異空間と化していたのだ
I had shifted into an alternate dimension!
How scary!
怖い～
Did that really happen?
本当にそんなことが
That's just because you were so shaken up,
それは動揺したお前が
you went and took the test
for the Greek class.
勝手にギリシャ語講座の試験を受けていただけだ
No! It was a curse! What's more,
three days later, in the morning,
違う　呪いだ
しかもその三日後の朝は
for some reason, my legs
had become as heavy as lead!
なぜか足が鉛のように重くなってしまったのだぞ
That's because the day before,
you had that marathon, right?
だから　その前日がマラソン大会だったろう
The power of the curse doll,
Belzenef, is real.
この呪い人形ベルゼネフの力は本物です
If you engrave the name of a person
that you hate into this doll's back,
この人形の背中に嫌いな人間の名前を刻めば
they are certain to meet with misfortune.
その相手は必ず不幸になるのです
This guy really is dark,
in more ways than one.
本当に色んな意味で暗いな　この人
He says he hates bright lights.
I wonder how he'll like this.
眩しい光が嫌いって
このくらいならどう
人殺し～
You murderers!
光　馨　なんてことを
Hikaru, Kaoru, how could you!?
You don't know the true
terror of black magic!
お前らには黒魔術の真の恐怖が分かっていない
Ah, I'm bored.
あ～つまんない
Isn't there anything fun we can do?
なんかおもしろいことないかなあ
無視されてる　部長の威厳が
My dignity as president...
is being ignored...
Say, Haruhi, we have a favor to ask.
ね　ハルヒ　お願いがあるんだけど
What is it?
The next day off we get...
今度の休みさ
...can we come over to your place?
お前んち　遊びに行ってもいい
Why would you?
なんでまた
Because we're awfully interested in it.
すごく興味あるんだけど
No way.
駄目
None at all?
どうしても？
No way. You'll just make fun of me.
駄目　どうせ馬鹿にするから
- No matter how much we ask?
- No way.
どんなに頼んでも？
駄目
I've also long been thinking that I should
pay my respects to Haruhi's family.
それは俺も　かねがねハルヒのご家族には
ご挨拶せねばと思っていたのだ
No way in hell.
絶対駄目
Then, let's do it this way. If you miss
じゃ　こうしようよ
どっちが光君でしょうかゲームで  当てられなかったら
in the "Which one is Hikaru- kun game,"
then as a penalty,
罰として　家に遊びに行く
we get to come over to your house.
Okay, which one of us is Hikaru- kun?
はい　どっちが光君でしょうか
You're Kaoru, and you're Hikaru.
こっちが馨で　こっちが光
Bzzzt! You got it wrong!
ぶ～　はずれで～す
No I didn't. You do look very similar,
but you are different.
外れてないよ
よく似てるけど　やっぱり違う
Say, Haruhi- kun,
ねね　ハルヒ君
once they cover whether they
part their hair on the left or the right,
髪型の右分けと左分けを隠されると
the difference between
Hikaru- kun and Kaoru- kun
光君と馨君の違いって全然分からなくなっちゃうんだけど
becomes completely indistinguishable.
How can you tell them apart?
どうやって見分けたの
Uh, well, let's see...
そうですね
If I had to say...
強いて言えば
光の言動のほうが馨より一割増し性格悪いですよ
Hikaru's speech and actions are
ten percent more ornery than Kaoru's.
"No offense intended"
I'm sorry, Hikaru!
ごめん　光
Well, I just don't mask anything,
and always express myself honestly,
まっ　僕は包み隠さず
いつも正直に発言してるだけで
底意地悪いのは馨のほうだけどね
so Kaoru is the one
who is more spiteful.
Don't go spinning this.
適当言わないでよ
Hikaru, I'm the one
who's always going along,
光のわがままな遊びに付き合ってやってんのは僕だろう
playing your selfish games, right?
I may be the one to suggest them,
言い出しっぺは僕でも　掘り下げんの馨じゃん
but you're the one
who gets into them, Kaoru.
If you don't like them, then just stop.
What are you, stupid?
いやなら止めろよ　馬鹿か　お前
You're too stupid to
see it for yourself, Hikaru.
あまりに光が馬鹿で見てなれないからだろう
Like how, even as you
were calling her a toy,
大体おもちゃとか言いつつさあ
you were so quick to make
some sort of pass at her.
なんだかんだですぐちょっかい出すし
Hikaru, you really are in love
with Haruhi, aren't you?
光ってさ　本当はハルヒのこと好きなんじゃないの
Huh!?
"What?!"
What!?
H-hey, you've got it all wrong!
You really are an idiot, Kaoru!
なに勘違いしてんだよ　やっぱ馬鹿だなあ　馨は
Yeah! There are some things you
can and can't say in this world!
そうだぞ　世の中には言っていいことと悪いことがある
For one thing, how is it that
I would fall for that little tanuki?
(Tanuki - A shape- shifting raccoon dog)
大体なんで僕がハルヒみたいな豆ダヌキを
What do you mean by calling
Haruhi a little tanuki!?
ハルヒを豆ダヌキ呼ばわりするとは　なにごとだ
Fantastic. This is fantastic.
素敵　素敵ですわ
"Powerful motor"
A beautiful, yet poignant four-sided
relationship around Haruhi- kun.
ハルヒ君を巡っての　美しくも切ない四角関係
What's more, two of the figures are twins,
しかもその中の二人は双子という泥沼的展開
bogged down by this development!
Renge could eat three
bowls of rice over this!
蓮華はもう　ご飯三倍いただけますわ
You stay out of this, otaku.
オタクは引っ込め
How mean! What a mean thing
to say to your manager!
ひどい　ひどいですわ　マネージャーに向かって
Renge- kun, I thought you liked Haruhi, too.
蓮華君　ハルヒのことを好きだったのでは
That's another matter. Everyone knows
that there's always more room
それはそれ
ホモ関係は別バラなのは今時常識ですわ
for homosexual relationships these days.
For that matter, I thought
you'd gone home to France.
ていうか　もうフランスに帰ったのかと思ってた
Well, it's too soon to start host clubs
in France, and it wouldn't go over.
だって　フランスでホスト部作ってみても
まだ早すぎていけないですもの
Enough already!
いい加減にしろよ
You're always getting into
my bed! You're such a pest!
人のベッドにいつも入ってきやがって　いい迷惑だ
That's because you seem so lonely, Hikaru.
光が寂しそうだから
仕方なく添い寝してやってんだろう　この馬鹿
I had no choice but to sleep
next to you, you idiot!
Who are you calling an idiot!?
You're doing worse in a number of classes!
何が馬鹿だよ　僕よか数学弱いくせに
Look who's talking! Hikaru,
maybe you should study linguistics more!
よく言うよ　光こそもっと語学勉強したほうがいいかもね
You grind your teeth too loud!
歯ぎしりうるさいくせに
Who is it that tosses in their sleep
and falls out of bed!?
寝相が悪くてベッド落ちてんの誰だよ
- Sex pixie!
- Sicko!
エロ河童
変態
Your mama wears too much makeup!
お前の母さん厚化粧
We're through!
絶交だ
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
おはよう
Good morning.
Hikaru? What's up with your hair?
光　どうしたの　その頭
Why is it pink?
なんでピンクなの
It looks good on me. Isn't it cute?
Starting today, the pink one is me.
似合うから　可愛いだろう
きょうからピンクが僕だから
I couldn't bear being mistaken
for Kaoru forever.
いつまでも馨なんかと間違われるの　堪えられないしさ
Good morning, Haruhi.
おはよう　ハルヒ
Kaoru, you went with blue.
馨はブルーなんだ
Last night, I had the rare chance
to gracefully sleep by myself,
ゆうべはせっかく優雅な一人寝だったのに
but I had a bad dream.
夢見悪くてさ
You see, my hair was dyed pink...
なにしろ　僕が髪をピンク
...of the most garish shade,
in this dream I was having.
なんて趣味の悪い色に染める夢見ちゃってさ
"Noontime recess in the refectory"
The A lunch.
Aランチ
On second thought,
やっぱBのパスタとDのサラダ
the B pasta and the D salad!
I mean, the F cappellini
じゃなくて　Fのカペッリーニにバルバリーガモ
with the barbarie duck- no,
set that aside,
は置いといて
and make it a foie gras poêlé,
フォアグラのポワレ　ペリグーソース添え
in périgueux sauce!
真似すんな　真似すんなって言ってるだろう
Stop copying me!
I just told you not to copy me, didn't I!?
Amazing. They're fighting in harmony.
すごい　ハモって喧嘩してる
I thought it was getting noisy in here.
なんか騒がしいと思えば
Are you two still fighting?
You're embarrassing the Host Club.
お前ら　まだ喧嘩してんのか　ホスト部の恥だぞ
It's the Host Club.
ホスト部だ
Oh my, the Host Club.
ま　ホスト部よ
The boys from the Host Club
are all together.
ホスト部の皆様がお揃いだわ
"Bunny Sumo"
Okay, break! You're both
to blame for this fight.
はい　そこまで
喧嘩でお成敗
Hika-chan and Kao-chan, go halfsies
on this cake, and make up! Okay?
ヒカちゃんもカオちゃんもケーキを半分こで仲直り
"Okay?"
Oh, but I want to eat some, too,
so I guess we have to go thirdsies.
でも　僕も食べたいから　三分の一こずつか
We can't split the strawberry,
so what do we do?
イチゴは分けらんないから　どうしよう
Maybe I should just take it.
僕もらっていいかなあ
"Irritation"
After all, I love strawberries,
so that's okay, right?
だって僕イチゴ好きだから　いいよね
Oh, but then, Hika-chan and Kao-chan,
do you like strawberries, too?
ヒカちゃんもカオちゃんもイチゴ好き
You're just making
the situation worse, so stop.
状況が悪化するから止めとけ
ハルヒ　学食で会うなんて珍しいなあ
Oh, Haruhi! Fancy running
into you in the refectory!
I was concerned about those two,
あのふたりが心配で　思わず付いて来たんです
and followed them
here without thinking.
I just have my box lunch,
so I wanted to eat it in the classroom.
お弁当だから　教室で食べたかったんですけど
A box lunch?
お弁当～
"Tamaki's Box"
Dear, here's your box lunch.
あなた　お弁当
Oh, but the heart-shaped sprinkles
might be a bit embarrassing.
でも　ハートの振り掛けなんて
ちょっと恥ずかしいかしら
Even if your box lunch did have
an embarrassing heart in it,
たとえ恥ずかしいハートの弁当でも
I would not hesitate to eat it!
俺は躊躇わずに食うぞ～
I don't know what you're talking about,
何を言ってるか分からんが
but I do know that your delusions
are always incoherent.
お前の妄想に脈絡がないことだけは分かった
Haruhi, here's a spot.
ハルヒ　ここ空いてる
Oh, okay.
What do you have in your box lunch?
弁当　中身なに
Yesterday's simmered leftovers,
some rolled omelet, and such.
昨日の煮物と玉子焼きとか
Switch with me. I ordered
something different from Kaoru,
僕のと換えてよ
馨と違うもの頼んだら　嫌いなものばっかなっちゃった
and ended up with all stuff that I hate.
Sure, okay...
いいけど
This is awfully lavish. I haven't ever
really eaten this sort of thing...
すごい豪華だな
こういうのってあんまり食べたこと
Delicious, isn't it?
Delicious, isn't it, Haruhi? Good.
おいしかったんだ　おいしかったんだね　ハルヒ
よかった　毎日でも食わせてやりたい
I'd like to let you eat that every day.
Well done, Hikaru. As a reward,
you can have my A lunch,
でかしたぞ　光  褒美に俺のAランチをやるから
- so let me have the box lunch.
- No.
その弁当をよこしなさい
Oh, don't say that.
そう言わず
I'm not about to.
やなこった
Haruhi, is that any good?
You want some of mine, too?
ハルヒ　うまいの
こっちのもやろうか
Here. "Aah..."
Butt out. Go away.
邪魔すんな　あっち行け
I think I'll eat in
the classroom after all.
やっぱり教室で食べよう
If this situation continues,
この状態が続くようなら
we're going to have to stop offering
the brotherly love package.
兄弟愛の設定を売りにするのも中止だなあ
Our designee rate is definitely down.
指名率は確実にダウンだし
Oh, Haruhi, this isn't something
that you should feel responsible for.
ハルヒは　別に責任を感じることはないんだよ
Even though your thoughtless comment
was the cause of this fight.
たとえ喧嘩の原因が
お前の心無い一言であったとしても　ねっ
"Smile"
"Don't worry about cleaning up
the dining hall, either."
"Smile"
He's clearly blaming me.
明らかに責めてるな
Hika-chan and Kao-chan
fighting with each other...
ヒカちゃんとカオちゃんが喧嘩するなんて  初めてだよねぇ
It's never happened before, huh?
Is that right?
そうなんですか
I've known them since pre-school.
We weren't in the same year,
僕幼等部の頃から知ってるもん
学年が違うから　しゃべったことないけど
so I never talked to them, but it seemed
like they always played together.
なんか　いつも二人だけで遊んでたよ
You're right. I've only known
them since middle school,
そうだな　俺は中等部からしか知らないけど
but they really stood aloof.
確かに浮いてたな
It seemed like except for themselves,
they kept everyone at a distance.
自分たち以外　誰も寄せ付けない感じで
Their personalities were several times
more warped than they are now.
今より数倍性格歪んでたし
Thinking about it that way, maybe this
fighting is a turn for the better.
そう考えりゃ　喧嘩なんていい傾向なのかもな
It means that their world is starting
to get a little larger, doesn't it?
すこしは世界が広がってきてるってことじゃないの
Maybe it's best to leave them alone,
under the circumstances.
この際ほっとくのが一番かも
Maybe it is a turn for the better.
いい傾向　なのかな
But then, if this is their first fight,
でも　初めての喧嘩なら
then maybe they need someone
尚更誰かが引き際を教えてあげないといけないんじゃないかな
to tell them when to
call it quits that much more.
They probably don't know how to
make up with each other, either.
たぶん　仲直りの仕方も知らないだろうから
"Music Room #3"
"No business today"
"Boom! Crash! Bang!"
After going this long,
haven't you gotten over it yet?
これだけやってもまだ気が済まないのか
You brothers are putting us out.
迷惑兄弟よ
We're putting you out!?
We're putting you out, you say!?
迷惑　迷惑だって
You've got to be kidding!
I'm the one who's put out!
冗談じゃない  迷惑してんのはこっちだよ
I'm the one who's got
the same face as Kaoru.
馨なんかと顔もそっくりでさあ
I'm sick and tired of being
mistaken for you! The truth is,
お前に間違われるのもうんざりだし
本当はお前なんか大嫌いなんだ
I hate your guts!
You took the words right
out of my mouth. Look at this!
そんなのこっちの台詞だよ
見ろ　猫沢先輩から買った呪い人形ベルゼネフだ
I bought this from Nekozawa- senpai-
Belzenef, the curse doll!
"Scared"
I'm writing your name on
this thing's back, Hikaru.
この人形の背中に  光の名前を書いてやる
From here on, you're going to meet
with lots of misfortune and sorrow!
これからお前は
たくさんの不幸と悲しみに見舞われるんだ
いい加減にしろ
Enough already!
You don't go bringing something
like this into a simple quarrel!
ただの喧嘩に　こんなもの持ち込むんじゃない
You both are to blame for this fight,
この喧嘩は二人とも悪いし
but you're even more to blame for
bothering everyone around you with it!
周りに迷惑掛けるのはもっと悪いよ
Now say you're sorry!
If you don't make up right now,
ちゃんと仲直りしな
今すぐ仲直りしないと
then I'll never let you come over,
as long as I live!
一生うちになんか遊びに来させないからね
Then, if we do make up, Haruhi,
じゃ　仲直りしたら
ハルヒの家に遊びに行ってもいいんだね
we can come over to your house, right?
"Blank"
I'm sorry, Kaoru. Even though
I was just following our script,
ごめんよ　馨
シナリオ通りとは言え
I'm not fit to be your brother,
to say such awful things to you.
あんなひどいことを言うなんて
お兄ちゃん　失格だな
Not at all. I'm the one
who was terribly worried
そんな
僕こそ　光に怪我でもさせたらどうしようって
about what I would do
if I hurt you, Hikaru.
すごく心配したんだから
Kaoru, I'll never let you go!
馨　もう離さない
Hikaru!
光～
Oh, you were faking the fight!?
なんだ　嘘の喧嘩だったの
Well, we were bored.
だって　退屈だったんだもん
T- they got me...
や　やられた
ひ　暇な双子
Twins with too much free time...
...are the devil.
悪魔だ
"Music Room #3"
"The Host Club is now open for business"
Thank goodness.
よかったですわ
Okay, let's play the
"Which one is Hikaru- kun game"!
どっちが光君でしょうかゲーム
Um, the one with the
pink hair is Hikaru- kun.
えっと　ピンクの髪が光君
大当たり
We have a winner!
You may have made up, but your hair will
still stay that way for a while, huh?
仲直りしても　しばらく髪の色はそのままなのね
Still, I'm glad it's easier to tell now.
でも　分かりやすくなって嬉しい
No it isn't.
違うよ
Today, the pink one is Kaoru,
and the blue one is Hikaru.
今日はピンクが馨で　ブルーが光だよ
You've switched your colors, huh?
色　交換したんだね
Have you noticed, Hikaru?
Up until now,
気付いてるか　光
これまで世界は
there were only two worlds:
"us" and "everyone else."
僕らと僕ら以外のふたつしかなかったけど
But for the first time,
a genuine gatecrasher has appeared.
始めて本物の侵入者が現われたんだ
喜べ　ハルヒ  お前に後輩が出来るぞ
Rejoice, Haruhi! You're going to
have seniority over someone now.
Someone new wants to join the club.
新しい入部希望者だ
But he's still in elementary school.
でも　その子まだ小学生ですよ
I'm afraid to imagine what that
kid will be like when he grows up.
末恐ろしいガキだな
Next time, " The Grade-School Host
is the Naughty Type"
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
お待ちしております